welcome back to another kdenlive video
欢迎回到另一段Kdenlive视频
editing tutorial in this video we're
编辑教程在这段视频中我们
going to learn how to apply text on
学习如何将文本应用于
overtop of a video and how to create a
以及如何在视频上创建
title introduction screen to your video
视频的标题介绍屏幕
project so to get started I'm just gonna
项目开始之前 我只想
drag in some video that I already have
拖入一些我已经拥有的视频
we'll do this we'll do one of these ones
我们会做这个 我们会做一个这样的
which one should we do how about this
我们该选哪一个呢？这个怎么样？
one of the parrot this is one we looked
其中一只鹦鹉 这是我们找的一只
at recently so we have this parrot here
最近 我们这里有一只鹦鹉
we can drag it down into our video one
我们可以把它拖到我们的视频中
track on our timeline and then I'm just
在我们的时间线上追踪然后我就
going to play and we can see what this
去玩吧 我们可以看到这是什么
video looks like so let's say maybe
视频看起来像是这样 所以我们假设可能
before this video starts we want to have
在这段视频开始之前 我们想要
a title introduction screen well to do
标题介绍屏幕做得很好
that we come up here and instead of
我们来到这里 而不是
clicking add clip so we'd likely we
点击添加剪辑 这样我们就有可能
would go to search a place on our
会去我们的星球上寻找一个地方
computer to add video or audio or
计算机以添加视频或音频或
picture we just go to this little drop
想象一下 我们只是去了一个小水滴
down here and we go to add title clip
在这里 我们将添加标题剪辑
and that'll bring up this dialogue here
这将在这里带来这段对话
we have this back this yeah this this
我们把这个拿回来了这个是的这个这个
view of these checker boxes this is a
查看这些复选框这是一个
transparent background and we can come
透明的背景 我们可以来
up here to these text tools we can click
在这里 我们可以点击这些文本工具
add text and we can click and then it
添加文本 我们可以点击 然后点击
creates something that says text on here
创建在此处显示文本的内容
and oops I think we can just start that
哦 我想我们可以开始了
way to double click it so we double
方法是双击它 这样我们就可以双击
click it and then we can go in and
点击它 然后我们就可以进去了
actually edit this text so I'm gonna
实际上编辑这篇文章 所以我要
call mine
打电话给我的
welcome to TJ free and then we come up
欢迎来到TJ Free 然后我们再来关注
here we have our selection tool up here
我们在这里有我们的选择工具
so we can click off the text click on a
所以我们可以点击文本点击
selection tool and then we can click and
选择工具 然后我们可以点击并
drag it around and move it we have
把它拖来拖去 我们有了
options for controlling it over here so
在这里控制它的选项 所以
we can change the font size if we select
我们可以更改字体大小 如果选择
all this we can actually change the font
所有这些我们实际上都可以更改字体
size and make it larger we can change
我们可以改变大小 把它变大
the font style so we can find a cool you
字体风格 这样我们就可以找到一个很酷的你
know font that we like to use with like
知道我们喜欢与Like一起使用的字体
Comic Sans and then we can change the
没有漫画 然后我们就可以改变
color so we didn't make it red if we
所以我们没有把它变成红色 如果我们
want to just keep in mind it's going to
我只想记住 它将会
be on a black background so it looks
在黑色背景上 这样看起来
like it's on these white squares now but
就像现在在这些白色方块上一样 但是
if we click down here at the bottom this
如果我们点击下面底部的这个
option that says show background it'll
显示背景的选项将
show
显示
well it's gonna be right now it's
好吧 现在就是了 它是
showing the background over topic would
在主题上显示背景将
it look like with the parent but if we
这看起来像是和父母在一起 但如果我们
were to put it before they would just be
如果把它放在他们之前
black so before the video the parrot
所以在视频之前是黑色的鹦鹉
starts to be black
开始变黑了
so but this is fine for adding it to
因此 这对于将其添加到
here and the outline of it is black we
在这里 它的轮廓是黑色的
can change the outline as well to a
也可以将大纲更改为
different color maybe make it green so
不同的颜色可能会让它变绿
it's the outline around the text oh and
这是文本周围的轮廓哦和
it actually we have to to make it up
实际上我们必须要补上它
apply right now it's on this completely
现在就涂 完全在这上面了
numb is completely transparent so we
Numb是完全透明 所以我们
have to bring this all the way up to
必须把这个一直带到
full full non-transparency I guess you
完全完全不透明 我猜你
can go it and so now the outline of our
可以走了 所以现在我们的轮廓是
text is green yeah and then it'll just
文本是绿色的是的然后它就会
stay there wherever we put it and if we
无论我们把它放在哪里 如果我们
want to there's some tools we can Center
想要吗？有一些我们可以集中的工具
it if we click this button that centers
如果我们点击这个居中的按钮
it with the video along the vertical
它与视频沿着垂直方向
axis and we can click this one to Center
轴 我们可以点击这一个居中
it along the horizontal access axis we
它沿着水平通道轴我们
can click this button to have it be all
可以点击此按钮将其设置为全部
the way over to the left hand side or
去左手边的路或者
all the way to the right hand side so
一直到右手边所以
some different options there but
有一些不同的选择 但
emotionally this right in the center
从情感上讲 这就是中心
yeah so let's click OK and let's just
好的 那么让我们点击OK 让我们
see what it looks like now so it's not
看看它现在是什么样子 所以它不是
on our video yet because what it does it
在我们的视频上 因为它所做的
creates an actual title clip up here as
在此处创建一个实际的标题剪辑
if it was a video or audio file so we
如果是视频或音频文件 那么我们
have to drag and bring it into one of
必须将其拖入其中一个
our video tracks so if we put on video
我们的视频跟踪 所以如果我们放上视频
too if we put it right in the middle of
如果我们把它放在中间也是如此
video too
视频也是
what'll happen is when we start playing
当我们开始玩的时候会发生什么
the video it'll wait till it gets to
它将等待的视频 直到它到达
that point and then it will overlay it
这一点 然后它将覆盖它
as soon as it gets to that point of the
一旦达到这一点
video this does have audio I thought in
视频这里面有我想过的音频
the last video I thought it didn't have
我以为它没有的最后一段视频
any audio but it turns out it does and
任何音频 但事实证明是这样的
so okay we're gonna go back over here
所以 好的 我们要回到这里
and now if we move it to the beginning
现在如果我们把它移到开头
of the video clip we'll see it'll play
我们将看到它将会播放
at the beginning but then it only played
一开始 但后来它只播放了
for a short amount of time and then that
在很短的时间内 然后
clip will disappear so by default the
剪辑将消失 因此默认情况下
video clip is 5 seconds long if we
视频剪辑有5秒长 如果我们
double click we can see the duration 5
双击我们可以看到持续时间为5
seconds so we can change this if we want
几秒钟 如果我们想的话我们可以改变这个
to be longer if we want to be 15 seconds
更长的时间 如果我们想要15秒
we can just type in here 1 5 hit OK
我们只需在这里输入15键就可以了
and it makes it 15 seconds long we can
它使它长达15秒 我们可以
also go to the end of the title clip if
如果出现以下情况 请转到标题剪辑的末尾
we hover over we get this cursor our
我们将鼠标悬停在我们的鼠标上方
cursor changes to these
光标更改为这些
horizontal arrows we can left-click and
我们可以左键单击的水平箭头
drag and make it the same length as our
拖动并使其长度与我们的
video if we want to have this text be
如果我们想让这段文字成为
over the video the whole time and we can
在整个视频中 我们可以
drag from the beginning too so we can
也要从头拖起 这样我们就可以
resize the clip that way and if we want
以这种方式调整剪辑的大小 如果我们希望
to be if we want this to be an
如果我们想让这成为一场
introduction and not have it be with a
介绍 而不是用一个
parent we can just move the parrot video
家长 我们可以把鹦鹉的录像带
forward to about here if we move it
如果我们把它移到这里 就会往前走
completely forward then we'll see the
完全向前 然后我们将看到
title of the video it'll just play like
视频的标题它会像这样播放
this and then it'll go directly from the
这个 然后它会直接从
title screen to the video clip of the
的视频剪辑的标题屏幕
parent and if we want to have a little
父母 如果我们想要有一点
overlap there we can do something like
在那里重叠 我们可以做一些类似的事情
this
这
so we can drag it and so we can actually
所以我们可以拖拽它 所以我们实际上可以
have this video overlap a little bit
让这段视频有一点重叠吗
with this parent video so now it'll play
有了这段家长视频 现在就可以播放了
and then it'll show the video of the
然后它会播放视频
parrot and keep the text on the screen
模仿并将文本保留在屏幕上
and then the text will go away all right
然后文字就不会再出现了
something cool we can do since this is
我们可以做一些很酷的事情 因为这是
black I'll just show you since we've
布莱克 我只给你看 因为我们已经
been doing effects in the past there is
在过去一直在做效果 有
a cool effect
酷炫的效果
that's called fade from black so if we
这就是所谓的从黑色褪色所以如果我们
drag on fade from black it'll fade in
拖着从黑色淡入 它将淡入
this video from a black background and
这段视频来自黑色背景和
since our title clip is already having a
因为我们的标题剪辑已经有了一个
black background like this it'll create
像这样的黑色背景会产生
this cool effect and it'll kind of the
这种很酷的效果
text will disappear and then it'll fade
文本会消失 然后会褪色
in so let's play this and see how it
所以让我们来播放一下
looks so it's just playing the text
看起来它只是在播放文本
right now and then we'll see a fade so
现在 然后我们会看到一个褪色
the parrot fades in as they're just just
鹦鹉渐渐消失
just being instantly there and we can
我们就可以
adjust the duration of this fade too by
调整此衰落的持续时间
using the scroll bar here and there's
使用滚动条这里和那里
also a fade out if we want to apply a
如果我们想应用一个
fade out to black we see a crease this
淡出到黑色 我们看到一个折痕
little red triangle and we can fade out
红色三角形我们就可以淡出
to black as well so at the end of the
到黑色 以及在年底
video clip it'll just fade into
视频剪辑会逐渐消失
blackness
黑度
that is using the text tool to to create
使用文本工具来创建
a title clip to create text overtop of
一个标题剪辑 以创建文本的顶部
video or an introduction title before
视频或介绍标题之前
the video starts pre-show you watch this
视频开始前你看这个
video hopefully you found it informative
视频希望你能发现它
join me on the next one see you then
下一个和我一起去 到时候见